<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Firewall on end.re</title><link>https://end.re/tags/firewall/</link><description>Recent content in Firewall on end.re</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright 2011-2016 Endre Szabo</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 07:20:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://end.re/tags/firewall/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Defeating CheckPoint VPN Route-All-Traffic Policy Enforcement</title><link>https://end.re/2018/06/12/ebp040_defeating-checkpoint-route-all-traffic-enforcement/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 07:20:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://end.re/2018/06/12/ebp040_defeating-checkpoint-route-all-traffic-enforcement/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Quite a bit of the enterprises have chosen to use CheckPoint VPN solutions to allow remote access to their corporate networks. This platform is widely used and it&amp;rsquo;s up to the security administrators to create the actual VPN security policies that apply to the connecting clients. Among these security rules, it&amp;rsquo;s very common to enforce all of the client&amp;rsquo;s traffic to go through the tunnel, be it destined to the corporate office or not, like Internet traffic that the corporation has noting to with. There is even a knowledge base entry on how to set up to &lt;a href=&#34;https://supportcenter.checkpoint.com/supportcenter/portal?eventSubmit_doGoviewsolutiondetails=&amp;amp;solutionid=sk101239&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Route all traffic from Remote Access clients, including internet traffic, through Security Gateway&lt;/a&gt;. On the sad side effect, when these rules apply, it is also impossible to connect to the VPN client itself from the same subnet the client resides on. And this leads to being unable to do SSH reverse port forwards to access corporate resources from outside of this client. However, this would be really useful in my scenario, where the connecting client is a Windows VM on my ArchLinux host, and I&amp;rsquo;d like to access over-the-tunnel corporate unix hosts using the friendly and very convenient to use OpenSSH &lt;em&gt;from&lt;/em&gt; the ArchLinux host and not from the Windows VM using PuTTY or something legacy dumb clients like that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using a netfilter rule with a trick on the ArchLinux host I managed to make easy to use transparent reverse port forwardings that also &amp;ldquo;complies&amp;rdquo; with the security enforcement rules of the VPN client.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>